Gregory Witek

hello@gwitek.com +31 (0) 6 39 87 70 17 Amsterdam, Netherlands

SUMMARY

I am an engineering manager with 3 years of experience in building and leading international, diverse, productive teams. Before that I spent 8 years working as a software developer in multiple industries like travel, fintech and adtech.

Currently I'm looking for a role at a dynamic company with challenging problems and a culture of engineering excellence.

WORKING EXPERIENCE

10/2020 — now: Engineering Manager at EclecticlQ

- Leading a team of 10 people
- Responsible for hiring developers, testers, technical writers
- Supporting product management and customer success teams
- Leading backend community of practice
- Actively supporting team by writing code and doing code reviews (primarily Python code)

09/2019 — 09/2020: Engineering Manager at CGLytics/Diligent

- Managed 2 product development teams, 11 people in total
- Overhauled team workflow: shortened release cycle, enforced testing and regular code reviews
- Introduced regular 1-1s, worked on annual goals and objectives

02/2019 — 09/2019: Lead Developer at NGTI/Swisscom

- Led initial implementation of new Swisscom mobile application
- Led building front-end for Swisscom data lake management tool

11/2014 — **12/2018**: **multiple roles** at Ascenda

07/2017 - 12/2018 Head of Engineering

- Managed 3 engineering teams with up to 16 direct reports
- Introduced remote-first culture in the whole company
- Set up the first overseas team in the company (in Manila, Philippines) I led this process from the idea, through planning, until hiring and onboarding first 4 employees
- Overhauled team structure and processes as the team grew
- Mentored developers of various experience, from interns to lead engineers
- Continued to be a hands-on engineer, with around 20% of time dedicated to programming

11/2014 - 06/2017 Lead Software Engineer

- Designed and led implementation of multi-tenant travel booking platform
- Oversaw implementation of API-based loyalty currency exchange

- Interviewed candidates, made hiring decisions together with CTO
- Built robust and scalable hotel search engine using Elixir
- Designed and built internal tools for other departments in the company
- Wrote 2 Ruby gems to facilitate managing business logic and configuration

01/2014 - 01/2015: Freelancing

• Helped to launch 3 projects, built mainly with Ruby on Rails, AngularJS and Backbone.js

09/2012 - 12/2013: Software Developer at Fyber

• Worked on ad serving engine handling up to 300,000 requests/minute

10/2009 — 11/2011: Software Developer at Netguru

• Worked on multiple client projects, including on-line games, e-commerce site as well as HR tools

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Expert knowledge of Ruby, working experience with Elixir, Python, PHP and TypeScript
- Extensive experience with frameworks like Ruby on Rails, Angular, VueJS, Laravel
- Proficiency in software architecture, refactoring, unit testing, working with legacy code
- Data storage solutions: Postgres, MySQL, MongoDB, Elasticsearch, Redis
- Cloud hosting: AWS, CloudFormation, basic familiarity with Azure and GCP
- Experience with a number of Agile and DevOps practices

EDUCATION

Poznan University of Technology: BSc in Computer Science, 2007 – 2011 Poznan University of Technology: MSc in Computer Science, 2011 – 2012

OTHERS

- Volunteered as a programming coach supporting initiatives like Rails Girls and Tech Ladies
- Spoke at a few international conferences: EuRuKo (Greece), WebExpo Prague (Czechia), RedDotRuby (Singapore), and more
- Used to co-organise programming meet-ups: PRUG in Poland, RubySG and Elixir User Group in Singapore
- Maintained Sorcery, a popular open source authentication library
- Sharing my knowledge and experience on my blog (<u>notonlycode.org</u>) and YouTube channel (<u>YouTube.com/c/NotOnlyCode</u>)